Hey
friends, if you work in the insurance industry
and you are an advisor or an
insurance consultant, then
where will today's video be for you because in today's
video I am going to tell you
what methods you
can use to sell insurance policies, what are the methods by which
you can find customers for yourself
and sell your policies,
so this video
is a must watch for every insurance agent and do
not skim the video at all friends
because in today's video I will
tell you what methods
you can use to find a line for yourself and
sell your insurance policies, so
let's continue this video today, so
hello friends, I am Amit Tyagi and you are
watching my YouTube channel, let's start
today's video friends, what happens is that when
any financial consultant or
insurance agent creates a prospect for himself, when he
searches for a drawing for you, then he has
various questions in his mind that friend,
where will I get new lines now,
how will I find people, in what way will I
talk to the people, the people I talk to do
not buy the policy  But
despite this, some different types of questions keep coming to your mind,
so what do you want?
You want them to meet people quickly
and buy our policy, but
sending insurance is not that easy. Friends,
first of all, before we know what are the
methods by which we
can sell insurance policies,
it is important to know why people do not
buy insurance. See, whenever we go to
buy something, if we go to buy something,
we will go to buy it when we need it. Nowadays, it is
very hot. In summer, people
need AC in the house because it is
very hot, so for that we
go to the market and buy AC
or we buy AC online.
Someone has difficulty in traveling, the
family has grown, first there was a scooter, then
came a bike, when the need for a bike arose, then we had to
buy a bike. After that, the family grew and the
bike did not work, so
we should have a car. When the need for a car
arose, then we buy a car from the showroom. In
this way, friends, as the
need arises, we buy the same thing,
but there is
no need for insurance.  Why is there no need for insurance?
Because when anyone goes to meet an LIC advisor,
it
becomes the duty of the advisor. It is your duty
that when you go to the client, when the
client buys everything he needs, then
you explain to him the need for insurance that
sir, you need insurance,
why is insurance necessary for you? To secure your family,
you have a small child, to
secure the future of that small child,
you should take a life insurance policy,
but the real life insurance policy
is such a kind of insurance which you
cannot buy when the need arises. If
you want to buy something, if you need it, then you
can buy it. If you need a car, then do
not buy it today, then do not buy it,
you can buy it after a month, but then
life insurance is not available when you need it.
If you fall ill, then you will
not get health insurance when you fall ill, this thing has to be
bought without a person. So,
when every insurance advisor
goes to England, he should go and explain to the client
why insurance is necessary, why life insurance is necessary
and
why health insurance is necessary. It is your duty to
explain this to your client when  Until you
understand the point, your point will
not be understood, he will feel that there is
no need for insurance, so from today onwards, make
this a rule, whenever you
meet anyone, from any line, from any
party, you meet anyone, you have to
explain the client's need,
why he needs insurance,
why he should take insurance, you do his
financial planning, you find out how much
his liabilities are, how much is his income, how much is
his
liability, explain to him, Kesar, you have
so many liabilities today, if you are not
with your family tomorrow, then from where will your family be able to bear all this,
how will the family of your house, which is
going today, survive, so sir, for this it is
necessary for you to have insurance,
your child is small, now he has cancer for a year,
when your child grows up,
he will need money for his education, tomorrow if God forbid
something happens to you, then how will the child's
school fees be paid, this is your duty,
explain this to your client, until you do not
understand, the client will not understand, the
need will not arise that he
needs insurance, right, so that this is what you are doing, this
Make this a rule from today, and now
I'll tell you how you
can sell insurance policies.
Friends, nowadays everything is turning digital.
You used to recharge your mobile phone for anything. Now,
you're online.
Friends, previously you had to go to restaurants to eat.
Now you can
order food online for free. So,
as times change and technology is
changing, we too will have to
change ourselves. Insurance has become a necessity today.
Use digital platforms and digitally remove yourself. So,
friends, the first way
you
can participate is to
learn Google advertising. If you
know how to run Google advertising, then
run an advertisement on Google. First,
learn how to run an advertisement on Google.
After learning, you
can generate a list from there. You'll find people
who search for insurance policies.
If someone searches Google for "I want to buy an
insurance policy,"
your advertisement will appear on the platform, and
they'll contact you and ask
you for an insurance policy.  If
you use Google Advertisement, you
can buy very good plans. Now the second
method I want to tell my friends is Facebook
Advertisement,
what is the difference between Google and Facebook? People who search on Google will
type 'I want to buy LIC policy', they will have to
type on Google that 'I want to buy
LIC policy', but you
can do targeting on Facebook, you don't have to search there,
you don't have to search keywords,
you can just do targeting there, you
can tell Facebook to show my
advertisement on Facebook only to those people
who are IIT passouts and their children are
small. Now think about it, if you are targeting,
you are targeting those people on Facebook
who are IIT passouts, right, and in that too
you have narrowed down the audience,
you show those people who are IIT
passouts and their children are small, children of
one year, two years, three years, then your
advertisement will show on Facebook to those people
who have received ₹500 from IIT and their
children are small, so just imagine that an IIT
passout  That
time is going on, if you live in Delhi,
you have targeted in Delhi
that brother, show these advertisements to those people
who work in MNC companies, if
someone works in an MNC company, then you
can target MNC company camp clothes,
you can do gender biased marketing,
you can do income biased marketing, you can
market people who buy luxury products in many ways, so
you can also do cutting in a very good way on Facebook,
you will reach those people directly,
you will have to invest a little money here
on Facebook ID and
on Google, you can invest according to your budget, if
you want to invest ₹500 then you can invest
₹500, if you
want to plant thousands of trees then you can plant thousands of trees, that is,
whatever your budget is,
you can set your budget according to that person,
Facebook will show your advertisement
to those people whom you target,
so you can generate a list very well from Facebook also,
you
can break the line from Facebook also and promote your insurance
policy  You can check these out. So
friends, if you don't know about Facebook and Google apps,
I've
created a quality series about them. You can go to
my YouTube channel and go to the playlist and
search for "digital marketing."
There, you'll find 35 videos.
In these 35 videos, I
taught you everything about how to run the Facebook app, the
Google app, and YouTube, and
how to build a website. It's a
complete course, so you
can learn by visiting my YouTube channel. Now, friends, the third
effective method is video
marketing.
You can also find niches through YouTube advertising.
You can also sell your products through YouTube advertising.
When you
see an advertisement, you must have noticed that
whenever you watch a video,
another advertisement appears in the middle of the video.
You can turn it off. So, you
can run your advertisement here
on YouTube. YouTube will show your advertisement to the
people you
want. If you target here,
show my YouTube advertisement to those people.
People who are watching videos about insurance,
then YouTube will show your ad only to those
people who are
watching videos about insurance. If you cut out a quote saying,
show my advertisement to those people who are interested in insurance, then
your advertisement will be
visible to those people. So just imagine
if someone is searching for an insurance policy and
he sees your advertisement and
you have selected the city there that is
Delhi, so you live in Delhi,
only the people of Delhi are seeing your advertisement
that if you
want to buy an insurance policy, you can contact me,
you can give your number below, so
what will the client do, he wants to buy a policy
and he has seen your attachment, so
he goes to your ad and sees your number and can
also call you and you
can also send your number there to you. Right, the
third method is video marketing, this is a very
effective method because friends,
in today's date, if someone wants to buy any item, then
before that he definitely watches its video
because on YouTube, if
you want to buy everything like this, then first you will
watch its video so that  What is this,
its feedback has been reviewed, how is
this, I want to see, if someone wants to
buy an insurance policy, then it is
not that first of all a person
buys the policy, it is not like that, someone has been
following him for 10 days, 15 days, one month, two months, six months,
he has been told about the insurance policy,
he fell in love with it and said that
I want to buy this Jeevan Lakshya policy, so
what will he do, he will go to YouTube and
watch the video, when he goes to YouTube and
watches the video and you see an advertisement in which you say that
if you want the
best insurance policy for yourself, then
you can contact me, if I myself
tell you which insurance policy will be
based, then when he sees your advertisement,
he will feel that every person will come to meet me, so this person
seems to be a good smoking monkey,
so I call these people,
once I understand the policy, then
what will he do, he can call you, he can make an appointment with you, he can
open the app,
so video marketing is also a very good
platform through which you can sell your business,
you can search for yourself online  So,
friends, the method is email
marketing. Now, friends, as far as email marketing is
concerned, I told you that email
marketing will ruin it. You
can email it, but you must have data.
Unless you have data,
you will email it. If you buy something from the market,
or if you email it,
it will not be effective. A
lot of mail goes there during this time.
A lot of it is there. So, never
buy something from the market and then
email it. First,
generate a list through Google, Facebook, and YouTube ads.
First, you will have people's numbers,
their email IDs, their names. So, when
you have 1,000, 2,000, or 4,000 numbers, then
you can email them.
Don't email data after buying from outside. You must have
your own data. You must have
data of people you know.
You can send it to people who are interested in insurance through email marketing. So,
friends, email
marketing is also a very good way to
sell policies. Try to find customers online
because people who are  You may
write to them sometime in the past and they forget, right there
you sent us an email for an officer, and
he saw that yes friend, this is an offer, okay,
he had submitted it six months ago, at
that time he did not have the funds, so he
thought, okay I will not take it now, I will take it later,
that thought he forgets,
you are not able to call him and he also forgets you, so
you emailed him and in
one go you emailed 10 thousand people, out of them
you got 5, 10, 20 clients
who got interested,
look at that offer, it is possible that they
bought your policy from there,
friends, one bus marketing point number
five which is very effective is SMS marketing,
friends, just like you do email marketing, you
can also do SMS, friends,
in SMS marketing you have to follow all kinds of roles
and you
cannot send promotional SMS on DND, you
send SMS to people who know you,
whose numbers you have, you
buy SMS from outside the market, to send bulk
SMS also, you first collect data  Collect
them from different platforms like Google, Facebook
and YouTube. Find lines before ads. Take their
numbers, their names, their email IDs
and when you get them, you
can send them bulk SMS. Bulk SMS
goes to everyone's mobile. Nowadays, if anyone
from the bank sends you this SMS, then the
SMS reaches you immediately.
People check the SMS. So, if you are
messaging a client, he made an inquiry 6 months ago, at that
time he was
not able to make a budget. Your message goes,
your name goes. If you are messaging him on some festival,
right? If you are
sending him a greeting on some festival, then
he will like it. You can send it by writing your name below. So the
client will know you
and later if he needs an insurance
policy or if he gets an order, you
can send this SMS alone and he may
buy your product someday. So friends, in today's
video I told you a very effective
way on how you
can sell insurance policies. So you should try this method,
but before that, when you go to the plan, it
is important for you to explain to the point
why insurance is needed when  Till then you will
tell why insurance is necessary
because when we need it, then we
go to buy things, until we
update our need, until we
create the cardamom urgent point, then there will be no way to
buy life insurance,
then different options will be shown like
I want to go to mutual fund, I want to go to
fixed deposit, I want to go to
post office, but if you
create his insurance need
then he will buy the insurance policy only, he will
buy it from you only, but you will have to create this net,
right, so friends, if you
liked my video then like the video
and do not forget to subscribe to my YouTube channel
and Satsang is played late at night,
I bring my YouTube live program
every Sunday, so if you want to ask me a question, then
you can join my YouTube live
program, so if
you have
set the notification on call in the balance near subscribe, then
you will see my live program
starting, you will get a notification, by
clicking on it you
can watch my live program and
you can ask your questions to it, I will try to
answer all your questions, so
today's  That's all in the video, thank you so much,
thank you very much to all of you.